<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Welcome on Alejandro Díaz&#39;s Portfolio</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/en/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Welcome on Alejandro Díaz&#39;s Portfolio</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.145.0</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/en/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>About me</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Alejandro Diaz&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/alex150.jpg&#34;&gt;
Hello! 👋 I&amp;rsquo;m Alejandro Díaz, a Telecommunications Engineer with over 10 years of experience in the ICT sector.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My career has evolved from network and web application design, through technical and innovation management, to the technical and commercial management of development and integration teams with clients from different sectors. I have led R&amp;amp;D projects, developed proprietary hardware and software solutions, and participated in multiple technology platforms, both in industrial and residential environments.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/contact/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;d like to get in touch with me for collaboration, consulting, or just to chat about technology, you can write to me directly by email or through LinkedIn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;📧 &lt;strong&gt;Email&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:alexdiaz17490@gmail.com&#34;&gt;alexdiaz17490@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt;
🔗 &lt;strong&gt;LinkedIn&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/alejandro-dch/&#34;&gt;Alejandro Díaz Chamorro&lt;/a&gt;
🌍 &lt;strong&gt;Location&lt;/strong&gt;: Pamplona (Navarra), Spain&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will soon integrate a form to facilitate contact directly from this website. 🚀&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How I control my home with Home Assistant</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/posts/how-i-control-my-smart-home/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/posts/how-i-control-my-smart-home/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For some time now, I&amp;rsquo;ve been using Home Assistant as the brain of my smart home. It&amp;rsquo;s an open-source platform that centralizes all my devices: lights, sensors, blinds, heating, security, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Home Assistant main panel&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/hass3d.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of its strong points is its flexibility: I have it running on a Raspberry Pi 4, with Zigbee, MQTT, and KNX integration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It allows me to automate things like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lower the blinds if I open the window and it&amp;rsquo;s cold&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stop the blinds from moving for safety when I open the windows&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Increase the speed of the heat exchanger if I detect a rapid rise in humidity in the bathrooms (shower)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Turn on the lights based on movement and brightness&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Control the underfloor heating according to rooms and schedules&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally, the control panel is fully customizable, and I&amp;rsquo;m starting to experiment with SCADA-style dashboards to view everything in real time.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
